<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Portfolio home page</title>
    <link>https://mrodrigues17.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Portfolio home page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrodrigues17.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Uncertainty with Bayesian Statistics</title>
      <link>https://mrodrigues17.github.io/blog/bayesian_statistics_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrodrigues17.github.io/blog/bayesian_statistics_overview/</guid>
      <description>Picture this: you just woke up, and as you go about your morning routine, the question lingers – will it rain today, and should you grab an umbrella? There&amp;rsquo;s a subtle assumption about the likelihood of rain on any given day, but you have the means to fine-tune this probability. Gazing out of your window, you observe the clouds overhead; this observation shifts your initial assumption, tilting it toward a higher chance of rain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Math Behind Machine Learning Algorithms: Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://mrodrigues17.github.io/blog/linear_regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrodrigues17.github.io/blog/linear_regression/</guid>
      <description>Despite its simplicity, linear regression is one of the most ubiquitous machine learning algorithms used today. Linear regression often ends up being a better model choice than more complicated ones because linear regression is easy to interpret and complicated models may overfit the data. Even though linear regression is considered simple in the realm of machine learning models, it is easy to treat models as black boxes without understanding the algorithm, and understanding how linear regression actually gets calculated lays the foundation for understanding more complex algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
